<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-04-10T19:35:51+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tebogo Tema</title><subtitle>Tebogo Tema is a software engineer in progress. The purpose of this blog/website is to document my journey,  feelings, thoughts and everything inbetween regarding software &amp; design.</subtitle><author><name>Tebogo Tema</name></author><entry><title type="html">Humble beginnings</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/04/Humble-beggings.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Humble beginnings" /><published>2022-04-04T19:08:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-04T19:08:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/04/04/Humble-beggings</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/04/Humble-beggings.html">&lt;p&gt;Hi there, I don’t know how you got here, but let me introduce myself weirdly. My name is &lt;strong&gt;Tebogo Tema&lt;/strong&gt;. I am a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Junior Software Engineer&lt;/code&gt; and a self-taught freelance &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Graphic Designer&lt;/code&gt;. My graphic design work ranges from &lt;em&gt;UI&lt;/em&gt; and some little bit of &lt;em&gt;UX&lt;/em&gt;, some merch clothing design, identity systems and a bit of everything in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Software engineering&lt;/code&gt; side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know what to touch in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Software Engineering&lt;/code&gt; field, but for the past 2 years I’ve done a lot; and I can’t say I have a specific field I am interested in, but I do almost everything. I enjoy both front end (not CSS lol) and a lot of backend coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, as I am starting my professional career in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Software Engineering&lt;/code&gt; as an intern for a very big company, I have decided to create a &lt;strong&gt;blog/ webite&lt;/strong&gt; to document the whole thing; from the struggles and hardships I am going to face, the technologies I will be exposed to, learning methodologies, my obscure thoughts on certain topics and other infinite thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It won’t be limited to Software Engineering, I will cover a range of topics in different fields; creativity, photography, design, music, study methods, and maybe a bit of markerting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you will be occasionally reading my blogs, just don’t take my words as final - I am really sure my thoughts and mindset will be super wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, these are my humble beginnings.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tebogo Tema</name></author><category term="first post" /><category term="start" /><category term="beginning" /><summary type="html">Hi there, I don’t know how you got here, but let me introduce myself weirdly. My name is Tebogo Tema. I am a Junior Software Engineer and a self-taught freelance Graphic Designer. My graphic design work ranges from UI and some little bit of UX, some merch clothing design, identity systems and a bit of everything in Software engineering side.</summary></entry></feed>