<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-10-04T21:58:55+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tebogo Tema</title><subtitle>Tebogo Tema is a software engineer in progress. The purpose of this blog/website is to document my journey,  feelings, thoughts and everything inbetween regarding software &amp; design.</subtitle><author><name>Tebogo Tema</name></author><entry><title type="html">Drifting away from my goals</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/20/Drifting-away-from-my-goals.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Drifting away from my goals" /><published>2022-04-20T01:24:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-20T01:24:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/04/20/Drifting-away-from-my-goals</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/20/Drifting-away-from-my-goals.html">&lt;p&gt;My last git commit was 20 days ago, and I was refactoring my domain code to be domain rich with objects. But I ended up introducing a lot of strings, I also overloaded my constructors with more than 5 arguments and so on because I was chasing a deadline; now I understand why there’s a lot of bad code in massive codebases because the manager wanted results quick, quick. There’s just a lot of bad code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I am writing this blog-ish thing is to acknowledge that I have been drifting away from my initial goal; To write the cleanest code and to become a better developer. But I stopped reading books, I stopped writing scripts, and looking at coding stuff. Instead, I went back to working with design clients to make money on the side because I have a certain goal in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m losing my shit. It’s not a nice feeling to drift away from something you held dearest and made a pledge that you’re gonna focus on it - then it ends up getting lost in time and getting shoved to the back of your mind. I feel like it’s a norm for humans to plan something, and then be okay with it even if it’s not executed, thus “New Year Resolutions” - damn, those things are a scam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re like me, you had a goal in mind, but never executed it. Does it bug you? If it does, what are you gonna do about it? Are you going to live most days with agony knowing you had to produce something but you didn’t. You know that thought after some years when you realize you could’ve done something but you didn’t? That regret?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I’ll pass on that. I cannot afford to do that. We should accomplish everything we set our minds to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine doing something you planned to do, but at your highest degree of capability? Imagine the results, crazy!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tebogo Tema</name></author><category term="Goals" /><category term="Passion" /><category term="Code" /><summary type="html">My last git commit was 20 days ago, and I was refactoring my domain code to be domain rich with objects. But I ended up introducing a lot of strings, I also overloaded my constructors with more than 5 arguments and so on because I was chasing a deadline; now I understand why there’s a lot of bad code in massive codebases because the manager wanted results quick, quick. There’s just a lot of bad code.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Depleting my hobbies as a creative</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/16/Depleting-my-hobbies-as-a-creative.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Depleting my hobbies as a creative" /><published>2022-04-16T23:15:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-16T23:15:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/04/16/Depleting-my-hobbies-as-a-creative</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/16/Depleting-my-hobbies-as-a-creative.html">&lt;p&gt;I often find myself busy in most cases; whether I am designing, coding, reading something, researching, or watching YouTube - I am occupied almost every time. I always have a hobby I tend to monetize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with design. I started off creating cartoon illustrations of my friends; I considered it a fun activity. Then I went to charging R50 per cartoon because I needed airtime to buy mobile data to access the internet everyday. I then found myself buying online courses on Udemy to learn how to design and use Adobe Illustrator efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From creating cartoons, I decided to go on a Graphic Design route and design logos for small businesses. And that was my start on monetizing a hobby; it later became a side hustle and then a job. I wasn’t doing it for fun or for my own amusement or to impress my friends. I was doing it to create some money on the side, crazy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hobbies are meant to be fun and keep you away from work-related stuff, something that keeps you away from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I know that I can basically turn any hobby into some sort of money-making medium. I want to start a hobby that wouldn’t allow me to do any of those; skateboarding. I have been looking at a lot of skateboarding videos on YouTube, and I swear that looks fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the lesson here is to avoid monetizing your hobbies. You will end up bored and consider the fun stuff “work”.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tebogo Tema</name></author><category term="Hobbies" /><category term="Design" /><category term="Creative" /><summary type="html">I often find myself busy in most cases; whether I am designing, coding, reading something, researching, or watching YouTube - I am occupied almost every time. I always have a hobby I tend to monetize.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Humble beginnings</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/04/Humble-beggings.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Humble beginnings" /><published>2022-04-04T19:08:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-04T19:08:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/04/04/Humble-beggings</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/04/Humble-beggings.html">&lt;p&gt;Hi there, I don’t know how you got here, but let me introduce myself weirdly. My name is Tebogo Tema. I am a Junior Software Engineer and a self-taught freelance Graphic Designer. My graphic design work ranges from &lt;em&gt;UI&lt;/em&gt; and some little bit of &lt;em&gt;UX&lt;/em&gt;, some merch clothing design, identity systems and a bit of everything in Software engineering side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know what to touch in Sofware Engineering field, but for the past 2 years I’ve done a lot; and I can’t say I have a specific field I am interested in, but I do almost everything. I enjoy both front end (not CSS lol) and a lot of backend coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, as I am starting my professional career in Sofware Engineering as an intern for a very big company, I have decided to create a blog/website to document the whole thing; from the struggles and hardships I am going to face, the technologies I will be exposed to, learning methodologies, my obscure thoughts on certain topics and other infinite things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It won’t be limited to Software Engineering, I will cover a range of topics in different fields; creativity, photography, design, music, study methods, and maybe a bit of markerting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you will be occasionally reading my blogs, just don’t take my words as final - I am really sure my thoughts and mindset will be super wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, these are my humble beginnings.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tebogo Tema</name></author><category term="First Post" /><category term="Start" /><category term="Beginning" /><summary type="html">Hi there, I don’t know how you got here, but let me introduce myself weirdly. My name is Tebogo Tema. I am a Junior Software Engineer and a self-taught freelance Graphic Designer. My graphic design work ranges from UI and some little bit of UX, some merch clothing design, identity systems and a bit of everything in Software engineering side.</summary></entry></feed>